RG 004:143, Torrington Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Torrington Probate Court records
1847-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Torrington District)
132.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1847-1935; Probate files, 1847-1976.
RG004_143
1912-011, 2011-028, 2011-029
Historical Note
Torrington, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1740, City incorporated January 1923
The Torrington Probate District was constituted June 16, 1847, from the Litchfield Probate District. It also served the municpality of Goshen beginning in May 1895. The Torrington Probate District merged with the New Hartford and Winchester Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Torrington Area Probate District which serves the municipalities of Barkhamsted, Colebrook, Goshen, Hartland, New Hartford, Torrington, and Winchester.
City of Torrington, Probate District chronology:
October 1740 - October 1742, Hartford District
October 1742 - June 15, 1847, Litchfield District
June 16, 1847 - January 4, 2011, Torrington District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Torrington Area District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books volumes 1-35, 1847-1935; Bond record books, 1881-1929; a volume of commitments titled, "Insane", 1911-1918. Contact the probate court to access original record books afver volume 35. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1847-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1847-1905 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-028 are arranged numerically 1-35. There are 3 bond volumes numbered 1-3 and a volume of commitments titled "Insane" numbered 1.
Probate files in accession 1911-012 are arranged alphabetically.
Probate files in accession 2011-029 are arranged as received from the probate court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-011 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-029.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Goshen; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Torrington
Places:
Goshen (Conn.); Torrington (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-028, Record books, 1847-1935, and Accession 2011-029, Probate files, 1881-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-15, 17-22, 24-25, 1847-1925; probate files, 1847-1880 (Accession 1912-011); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-011 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 10, 1912 (1847-1935).
The record books in accesion 2011-028 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 4, 2010.
The probate files in accession 2011-029 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 4, 2010; January 3, 2011; June 29, 2011; September 28, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1847-1935; 21 cubic feet (39 volumes); 2011-028
  - Records, 1847-1857 (Volume 1)
    On spine: "Miscellaneous"
  - Records, 1857-1867 (Volume 1)
  - Decrees, 1857-1883 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1867-1878 (Volume 4)
  - Decrees, 1873-1887 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1878-1886 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1886-1891 (Volume 7)
  - Decrees, 1887-1894 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1891-1895 (Volume 9)
  - Decrees, 1894-1899 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1895-1898 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1898-1900 (Volume 12)
  - Decrees, 1899-1904 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1899-1903 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1903-1905 (Volume 15)
  - Decrees, 1904-1908 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1905-1907 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1906-1908 (Volume 18)
  - Decrees, 1908-1911 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1908-1909 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1909-1911 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1911-1913 (Volume 22)
  - Decrees, 1911-1915 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1913-1914 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1915-1917 (Volume 25)
  - Decrees, 1915-1917 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1917-1919 (Volume 27)
  - Application letters of administration, 1917-1927 (Volume 28)
  - Applications to sell and return of sale of real estate, 1918-1935 (Volume 29)
  - Decrees, 1917-1922 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1919-1923 (Volume 31)
  - Return of claims, 1916-1935 (Volume 32)
  - Wills, 1919-1935 (Volume 33)
  - Inventories, 1918-1930 (Volume 34)
  - Accounts, 1919-1925 (Volume 35)
  - Bonds, 1881-1903 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1903-1918 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1918-1929 (Volume 3)
  - Insane, 1911-1918 (Volume 1)
- Probate files, 1847-1905; 5.25 cubic feet; 1912-011
  - Abeling - Barber (Drawer 1)
  - Barker - Botek (Drawer 2)
  - Bouns - Butler (Drawer 3)
  - Cable - Coe (Drawer 4)
  - Cole - Dayton, J. (Drawer 5)
  - Dayton, K. - Forrest (Drawer 6)
  - Fowler - Hammond (Drawer 7)
  - Harrigan - Hogan (Drawer 8)
  - Holly - Hulbarsz (Drawer 9)
  - Hull - Marshall (Drawer 10)
  - Martin - Murray (Drawer 11)
  - Neary - Pond (Drawer 12)
  - Potter - Scoville, L. (Drawer 13)
  - Scoville, M. - Sullivan (Drawer 14)
  - Swanson - Wadhams, L. (Drawer 15)
  - Wadhams, M. - Whiting, H. (Drawer 16)
  - Whiting, I. - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 17)
- Inventory Control Book, 1847-1905; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1912-011
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1881-1976; 106 cubic feet; 2011-029
  Files arranged as received from Probate Court
  - Probate files (Drawer 1-106)